よく飽きねーな、朝からずっと匂い嗅ぎまくってさ
Don't you get bored?
You've been sniffing stuff all day.
い…いい加減に！しろよ！
Cut it out.
う…ててててて…
Ouch...
あれ…？おかしいな
Huh? I feel dizzy...
Party is over
But I still wanna dance
I can't even sleep
Someday, one day my passion's fire will
From the beginning I knew
One day the flames would die out
Hey, I thought I didn't need anything
But even now, I'm so serious
Ah... I still have time to make it
Ah... but I'm gonna burn it up, baby
Sorry darling, it's not that easy
But surely it's not that bad either
Give me fire
Light it up, baby.
I'm gonna burn it up, yeah
Party is over
Sorry darling Hurry up
Ah... I still have time to make it
Give me fire
Light it up, baby.
I'm gonna burn it up, yeah
#9 The story of the mercilessness
What do you want?
なな…何だい？
Dororo...
どろ…ろ
Dororo, body, hot...
どろ…ろ。からだ…。あ…つい
Sick, huh? Sorry, but I'm just a farmer.
病か…あいにく俺は百姓だ。
I ain't got no medicine.
Don't know how to help.
薬もねえし、どうすりゃいいかわかんねぇ。
Sorry, kid.
すまねぇな
Mama?
おっかちゃん…？
Is something the matter?
どうかしましたか？
Mama...
おっか…ちゃん…
Don't worry, you just sleep some more.
大丈夫。まだ眠っていなさい。
This is a temple.
Your friend brought you here.
ここは寺です。お連れの方が運んでくれたのですよ
Hyakkimaru?
あにき…
Oh no!
あにき！
You mustn't!
いけません
No! He'll leave me behind again.
あにき！また…また置いてかれちまう
Don't worry, he just went
to go fetch some water.
安心なさい。水を汲みに行ってもらっているだけです
Nobody is going to leave you behind.
誰もあなたを置いていったりしません
I hate Manjushage, the red spider lilies.
曼珠沙華は好きじゃねえ。
They remind me of my papa and mama.
お父ちゃんとおっかちゃん思い出しちまう
Were they such terrible parents?
そんなにひどい親御さんだったのですか
No!
そうじゃねえ！
That's not it.
そうじゃねえ…
Papa and Mama were strong and kind.
お父ちゃんもおっかちゃんも、強ぇしあったけぇんだ
Papa, take me with you next time.
お父ちゃん。次はおいらも連れてってよ
If your mama says okay.
おっかちゃんがいいって言ったらだ
Those samurai had it coming.
あの侍ども、いいザマだったぜ。
Right, Boss?
ねぇ、おかしら
All shivering pale like they saw a ghost.
どいつもこいつも、青瓢箪みてえなツラして震えてやがったな。
We wouldn't even lose to Daigo's army now.
今の俺たちなら、あの大軍にだって負けやせんよ
No doubt.
ちげぇねぇ
Who should we get next?
次はどこを狙いやしょうか
Let's see.
そうだな…
Go on to Mama now.
ほら！おっかちゃんのところに行ってろ
I wanna listen.
おいら聞いてたいのに
Dororo, I'll play with you later.
どろろ。後で遊んでやっから
Humph, no way.
フン、だ。べーっ
Mama!
おっかちゃん！
I want to go with Papa.
おいらもおとうちゃんと行きたい！
I told you, no.
ダメだって言ってるだろ？
I can beat up the bad guys, too.
おいらだって悪いやつくらいやっつけられらぁ！
When you get a little bigger, okay?
もう少しおっきくなってからだよ
I wanna go now! Please!
行きたいったら行きたい！行きたい！行きたい！
Do you want me to hang you up
on a tree again?
言うこと聞かないと、また木に吊るすよ
What's with the puffed cheeks?
Trying to be a squirrel?
どした、ほっぺた膨らまして。リスの真似か
I'm no squirrel.
フン。あんなに膨らむかい
Whatcha doing?
何してんだ
Throwing rocks. I can't use a sword,
so I'll beat the bad guys like this.
石投げ。おいら刀使えねえから、
こいつで悪い奴をやっつけて…やんだ！
I like the way you think.
ふぅーん。そいつはいい心がけだぞ。
But you know Dororo, you can't live
on just strength from now on.
だがな、どろろ。これからの世の中は、力だけじゃ生き残れねぇ
Big trouble!
大変だぁーっ！
The samurai are coming!
侍どもが攻めてきたぞーっ！
Dororo, you hide over there.
どろろ！そっちに隠れてろ
-Boss!
-Came for revenge, huh.
お頭！
-仕返しに来やがったか！
You'll pay for what you did, you crooks!
よくもやってくれたなこの悪党ども！
We only strike samurai.
ハッ！俺たちが狙うのはお前たち侍だけだ
Don't take us for some lowlife scumbags!
そこらの悪党と一緒にすんじゃねぇ！
Shut up!
ぬかせー！
-Dororo!
-Mama.
どろろ！
おっかちゃん！
Mama...
おっかちゃん…
Don't worry.
Your papa will always be your papa.
心配ないよ。お父ちゃんはお父ちゃんだ
Yeah...
ん、んん…
So, what now?
こっからどうしやす
We'll round up some men and regroup.
すぐに仲間を集めて立て直す。
We can't run away now,
for the sake of the men we lost.
ここで逃げちまったら、死んだ奴らに合わす顔がねぇ。
Ojiya, we'll have to move around
for a while.
お自夜、しばらく転々とすることになるぞ
I guess so.
そうだね
During these days, brigands
scourged the lands of every region.
この時代、各地に野伏せりと呼ばれる野盗集団が存在し
Their brutality brought fear
into the hearts of the helpless.
力なき人々を恐れさせた
Samurai who'd lost their lords
formed their own bands.
主を失った侍たちが徒党を組む…
And the poor joined them
in order to make a living.
貧しき者たちが生きるために身をやつすなど、
Each had their own reasons for joining.
そこに至る理由は様々
Hibukuro's band consisted of farmers,
and they only assaulted samurai.
その中にあり、農民たちが集い、かつ、侍のみを襲っていた火袋たちは
They were quite a rare band of brigands.
きわめて特殊であったといえよう
Hey, Papa?
ねえ、お父ちゃん
Why do you go beat up the samurai?
お父ちゃんたちは、どうして侍をやっつけてるの？
It's to teach them a lesson.
そうやって奴らに教えてやってんのよ。
So that they'll treat us right.
俺たちも生きてる人間なんだってな
Samurai don't even get that?
生きてる？侍はそんなこともわかんないの？
I'd say they've learned their lesson now.
いや…奴らも十分思い知ったんじゃないですかねぇ
What do you mean?
どういう意味だ
Take a look around.
You've built up a pretty tough band.
見てくださいよ。ずいぶんと腕のいい子分たちが集まった。
Why don't you look towards the future now?
お頭も、そろそろ先を見たらどうなんでぃ。
If you play your cards right,
the lord will give you a good position.
うまく領主に取り入れさえすれば、いいご身分が手に入りやすぜ？
Itachi, have you forgotten
what they've done to us?
イタチ…あたしらが受けた仕打ちを忘れたのかい？
Because of the wars
those lords started up,
領主たちが勝手に始めた戦のせいで、
our families were killed
like they were nothing but bugs.
親も兄弟も虫みたいに殺されて、
They burned down our village
that we built up together.
みんなで作った村も焼かれちまったんじゃないか
Yeah, I've forgotten those things.
フンッ！俺は忘れちまいましたねぇ。
Can't hold on to things that've passed.
過ぎたことにいつまでもこだわってちゃいけねぇ。
You gotta join forces with the samurai
from here onwards.
むしろ、これからは侍どもと手を組んで出世しなきゃ…
You're a disgrace!
この恥知らずが！
I didn't say anything wrong.
お…俺ぁ、間違っちゃいねえと思いやすがねぇ
Say that one more time
and you'll get a mouthful of this.
もう一度行ってみろ。その口にこいつをぶち込んでやる
Fine.
わかりやしたよ…
The Yanagimoto guys are worn out
from fighting Daigo.
柳本のやつら、醍醐との戦で疲れ切ってる
Now's our chance.
やるなら今ですぜ
Charge!
行けぇーっ！
-No!
-Mama!
あんたぁーっ！
おっかちゃん！
Ojiya, Dororo!
お自夜！どろろ！
Explain yourself, Itachi!
何故だ、イタチ！
This whole place is going to be
a battlefield in no time, Boss.
お頭…すぐにこの辺り一帯も、ぜーんぶ戦場になっちまう。
It's the age of the samurai.
もう侍の時代なんだ
You can't make a living
being stubborn like you.
これからの世の中、あんたみたいに融通が利かねぇんじゃ、
食っていけねえんだよ。
I'm taking your men with me.
残った子分は俺が頂いとくぜ
You coward...!
この卑怯もんが！
I'll tear you to pieces!
八つ裂きにしてやるっ…ぐわぁっ！
No!
あんた！
You can't even stand on those legs now.
その足じゃあ立つのもやっとだろう。
Too bad you can't tear me to pieces.
残念だったな、八つ裂きにできなくて
The flames of Hibukuro have gone out,
and he's just a sack of rags now.
火袋の火が消えて、ズタ袋になっちまったな
No...
あんた！
Itachi!
イタチ！
Let's find something to eat.
食いものを探す
Mama...
おっかちゃん…
Is this what hell is like?
地獄ってこんなとこかい？
I don't know,
but it might not be as bad as this.
さぁ…でも、ここよりはマシかもしれないよ
Why are Manjushage the color of blood?
曼珠沙華って、どうして血みたいな色をしてるんだろう
They might've soaked up the blood
of those who died in war.
戦で死んだ奴らの血を吸ったのかもしれねぇな
Stop that. You're scaring the poor child.
いい加減なこと言って…怖がらせないでくれ
Have mercy!
やめてくれぇ！
It took years for us
to build this village up.
この村は俺たちが何年も何年もかけて、ようやくここまでになったんだ！
Silence! We must not have any obstacles
in the way of our army.
黙れぃ！我が軍が攻めいる経路にはいかなる障害もあってはならぬ。
These are our lord's orders!
これは領主様の命令ぞ
No, please!
そんな！
How are we supposed to live on?
じゃあ俺たちは、これからどうやって生きていけばいいんだ！
Hands off!
離さんか！
Burn them down!
さっさと焼けぇ！
That's too cruel.
ひでえよ…こんなの…
The lords and samurai think they can
do anything if it's for a war. But...
領主も侍も、戦を名目にすりゃ何をしてもいいと思ってるんだ。でも…
Please, don't anymore.
あんたは…もうやめとくれ
Let's go.
行くぞ
Stop right there.
そこのお前、止まれ！
I'll never forget that huge pole sword.
その大長巻、忘れようにも忘れられん。
Our homes were raided by brigands,
and my friends were all killed.
野党に屋敷を襲われ、仲間を全て殺された。
I could never understand
why I alone was left to live.
自分だけが生き残ったのは何の因果かわからぬままだった。
But now I know.
それが今わかった！
Hibukuro!
火袋ーっ！
You bastard!
貴様ぁ！
This is how you use a spear!
槍っていうものはな…こう使うんだ！
Papa... Papa...
お父ちゃん？お父ちゃん
Papa... Papa...!
お父ちゃん！お父ちゃん！
Papa...
お父ちゃん…！
Mama, I'm hungry.
おっかちゃん…おいらお腹空いたよ
The war will end some day.
戦は終わる。
Once it does,
you'll be able to eat all you want.
そうすれば、お腹いっぱい食べられる
You mustn't lose to it until then, Dororo.
それまで絶対に負けちゃだめだよ。どろろ
You there.
お前さん方
Yes?
はい？
It may be none of my business,
余計なお世話かもしれんが、
but samurai are giving handouts
over at the temple down that way.
この先を登ったお寺で、お侍さんが施しをしてくださっとる。
You should go there.
行ってみるといい
Itachi!
イタチ…はっ！
Well, what a surprise.
こいつは驚いたな
What are you doing here?
あんた、何してんだい？
I got nice and cozy with the lord,
いやねぇ、うまく領主さんに取り入ったはいいが、
but now I've gotta achieve something
out on the battlefield.
今度は戦場で手柄を立てにゃあならんのさ
There are lots of brigands around here.
この辺りにゃ野伏が多い。
This is the quickest way
to gather up some men.
必要な人手を集めるにはこうするのが手っ取り早いのよ
So, how's Boss doing?
それより、お頭はどうした。
I see.
…そうかい…
How've you been, Dororo?
久しぶりだなどろろ。
Looking good... or maybe not.
元気そう…じゃあ、ねぇか
Don't, Dororo.
やめな！どろろ
But, I...
でも…でもおいら…
Listen to your mama.
おっかちゃんの言うことが聞けないのかい？
Fine.
わかったよ…
Almost out. Don't got enough for everyone.
そろそろ終わりだ！全員分はねぇからな！
Wait here, Dororo.
待ってな、どろろ
Please, give me some!
私にもちょうだい！
You ain't got a bowl.
お前…椀持ってねぇじゃねぇか！
Sorry, but we don't got any more
to lend you.
こっちが用意した分はもうなくなっちまったんだ。わりぃな
Then pour it here.
かまわないよ！ここに！
But...
いや…！でも…
Give it to her.
言う通りにしてやれ
O-Okay.
へっ、へい…
Mama, are you okay?
おっかちゃん…大丈夫？
Of course. Eat it slowly now.
ああ。さ、慌てて食べるんじゃないよ
It's yummy. Aren't you going to eat?
おいしいよ。おっかちゃんは？
Don't worry, eat up now.
いいから全部お食べ
I didn't want to see you like this.
Sunken down so low.
あんたのそんな姿は見たくなかったぜ。落ちぶれちまいやがって
Dororo!
どろろ！
You can't live on strength alone
from here on out.
これからの世の中は力だけじゃ生き残れねぇ。
Use your brains.
ここだよ、ここ
Gotta be smart, or you'll die.
賢くねえ奴は…死ぬぞ
You jerk!
バッ…バカヤロー！
Mama?
おっかちゃん？
Mama!
おっかちゃん！
I'm fine. I just need to rest...
大丈夫だよ…少し休めば…
Mama...
おっかちゃん！
Hold on, I'll go find some food.
待ってて。おいら、なんか食べモン探してくる
Come here, Dororo.
おいで、どろろ…
The war will end some day...
い…つか。戦…は、終わる…
You mustn't lose to it until then...
それまで…負け…ちゃ…
Mama? Mama!
おっかちゃん？…おっかちゃん！
Answer me, Mama.
返事しておくれよ。おっかちゃん！
I won't say I'm hungry anymore,
so please don't die.
おいらもう腹減ったなんて言わないから、だから死なないでよ！
Mama, Mama...!
おっかちゃん…おっかちゃん！おっかちゃん！
That's why I'm never going to give up.
だから、おいら…絶対、負けねぇ。
I'm not going to lose to some war...
戦…なんかに…
I know not how you two are related.
どのようなご関係かは存じませんが、
But it must be difficult
traveling with such a young girl.
年端の行かぬ女の子を連れての旅はさぞかし難儀でしょう
I pray that Buddha will bless you
on your journey.
どうかあなた方の旅路に、仏様のご慈悲がありますように。
我建超世願…
That nun said I had the 3-day fever.
あの尼さんが言ってたけど、おいら、三日病みにかかってたんだって
I don't remember anything that happened.
寺にいる間のことは全然覚えてねえや
Thanks for not leaving me behind.
あにき。置いてかないでくれてありがとな
Oh yeah. You can't see,
but she washed my clothes, too.
あっ！そうだ！あにきは見えねぇだろうけど、
着物も洗ってもらったんだ！
See? They don't smell anymore.
ほれ。臭わねぇだろ？
Wait a minute...
ん？待てよ…
So I had my clothes taken off?
てことは、おいら…あにきの前で服を…
Hey, did that nun say anything about me?
あ、あにき。あの尼さん…おいらのこと、なんか言ってた？
Did she?
言ってたのか？
Hey, I know you can hear me.
あ…あにき！おい！聞こえてんだろ？
Say something, come on.
なんとか言え！おい、こらあにき！
Can you hear me?
Hey, I'm talking to you.
おい、あにき聞こえてんのか？黙ってないで何とか言えよ！あにき！
There was a former midwife who worked here
かつて城勤めをしていた産婆から
who had heard that a baby without limbs
was sent floating down a river.
両腕・両足のない赤子を川に流したと聞いたものがおります
And 3 days ago,
さらに3日ほど前、
a commander pursuing an Asakura spy
was injured severely by an unknown man.
朝倉の密偵を追っていた国頭が何者かに襲われ、深手を負いました
The commander said the man's arms
were prosthetics.
国頭によれば、その者の両腕は作り物であったと…
Sorrow scatters in the wind,
piling up to form shadows
Our footsteps admonish
indifference in such verbose ways
As I peek into your fathomless eyes,
I lose my composure
Is there any hope
in the place I am heading to?
I feign amusement and laugh
because this road is so dark
I will be there to shine the light
I'm used to playing at saying goodbye,
but I cried when I waved to you
Our fiery woes fade... and fade...
until night falls upon us
If I knew tomorrow would be so mundane,
I wouldn't have said that I wanted to live
I know it's futile but can't help dreaming
of a future... a future... you are to blame